Guide to the Yale Alumni Fund Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Alumni Fund records
1768-1990
RU 538
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
53.5
(85 boxes)
The records consist of the 13th annual report of the Board of Directors, meeting minutes, executive committee documents, ledgers, correspondence, donation card files, pledges, and bequests documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Alumni Fund.
Yale Alumni Fund
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 7-B (YRG 7-B), Records of offices with specific development responsibilities at Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the 13th annual report of the Board of Directors, meeting minutes, executive committee documents, ledgers, correspondence, donation card files, pledges, and bequests documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Alumni Fund..
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Educational fund raising; Fund raising; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale Alumni Fund; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Finance
- Records, 1768-1947; Accession 1948-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Correspondence and Ledgers record the contributions to the Alumni Fund
  - Correspondence
    - 1890-1895 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
    - 1896-1899 (Box 2, Folder 6-10)
    - Notebook on Alumni Fund, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ledgers: Daily Entries of Contributions
    - 1899-1918 (Box 3, Folder 12-15)
    - 1918-1932 (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
    - 1932-1943 (Box 5, Folder 19-21)
    - 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 22-24)
  - Ledgers: Daily Entries of Contributions by Class
    - 1768-1942 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 1847-1926 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - 1854-1942 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - 1905-1924 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - 1910-1941 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Semi-Centennial Celebration and Campaign: correspondence, programs and memoranda, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Donation cards, 1935-1950; Accession 1976-A-001
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  - Yale College
    - Alumni records - card file
      - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
      - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1937 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
      - 1938 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1938 (cont'd) (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
      - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
      - 1941 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 1941 (cont'd) (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
      - 1942 (Box 5, Folder 16-19)
      - 1943 (Box 5, Folder 20-22)
      - 1943 (cont'd) (Box 6, Folder 22-25)
      - 1944 (Box 6, Folder 26-31)
      - 1945 (Box 7, Folder 32-41)
      - 1945 (cont'd) (Box 8, Folder 42-43)
      - 1946 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - 1947 (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
      - 1948 (Box 8, Folder 47-48)
      - 1949 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      - Sheffield, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - Sheffield, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - Class Agents, 1881-1931 (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - Class Agents, 1932-1943 (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - Class Agents, 1943-1950 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Graduate Schools
    - Forestry, 1930-1946 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Law, 1872-1940 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Law, 1891-1949 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Law, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Medicine, 1875-1927 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Medicine, 1927-1940 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Medicine, 1941-1947 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Medicine miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Music, 1897-1945 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Nursing, 1926-1946 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Agents (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Faculty (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - Additional unknown degrees (Box 12, Folder 67-71)
- Donation cards, 1858-1934; Accession 1976-A-002
  - Alumni donation card files
    - 1858-1888 (Box 1)
    - 1888s-1891 (Box 2)
    - 1892-1894 (Box 3)
    - 1894s-1895s (Box 4)
    - 1896-1897 (Box 5)
    - 1897s-1898s (Box 6)
    - 1899-1900 (Box 7)
    - 1900s-1902 (J) (Box 8)
    - 1902 (K)-1903s (Box 9)
    - 1904-1905 (Box 10)
    - 1905s-1906s (Box 11)
    - 1907-1908 (M) (Box 12)
    - 1908 (N)-1909 (Box 13)
    - 1909s-1910s (Box 14)
    - 1911-1912 (O) (Box 15)
    - 1912 (P)-1913 (Box 16)
    - 1913s-1914s (Q) (Box 17)
    - 1914s (R)-1916 (E) (Box 18)
    - 1916 (F)-1917 (O) (Box 19)
    - 1917 (P)-1918 (Box 20)
    - 1918s-1919s (R) (Box 21)
    - 1919s (S)-1921(O) (Box 22)
    - 1921(P)-1922s (Box 23)
    - 1923-1924 (J) (Box 24)
    - 1924(K)-1925(R) (Box 25)
    - 1925(S)-1926 (Box 26)
    - 1926s-1927/1927s (Q) (Box 27)
    - 1927/1927s (R)-1928s (J) (Box 28)
    - 1928s (K)-1929s (Box 29)
    - 1930-1931(G) (Box 30)
    - 1931(H)-1932(L) (Box 31)
    - 1932 (M) -1933(Q) (Box 32)
    - 1933(R)-1934(R) (Box 33)
    - 1934 (S)-1934 SandE (Box 34)
    - miscellaneous addresses (Box 35–37)
- Pledges and bequests, circa 1950-1980; Accession 1982-A-008
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2055.
  - "Cutler Mail" Returned Pledges, 1979-1980
    - A-F (Box 1)
    - G-M (Box 2)
    - N-Z (Box 3)
  - Alumni Fund Pledges
    - A, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - B, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - C, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3 - 4)
    - D, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - E-F, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - G, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - H, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - I, J, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - K, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - L, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - M, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mc, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - N, O, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - P, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Q, R, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - S, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 17 - 18)
    - T, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - U, V, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - W, X, Y, Z, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Completed Bequests, 1960's-1970's
    - A (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - B (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - C (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - D (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - E, F (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - G (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - H (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - I, J (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - K (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - L (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - M (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - N, O (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - P (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Q, R (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - S (Box 7, Folder 36 - 37)
    - T (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - U, V (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - W, X, Y, Z (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Bequests Pending
    - A (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - B (Box 8, Folder 42 - 43)
    - C (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - D (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - E, F (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - G (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - H (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - I, J (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - K (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - L (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - M (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - N, O (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - P (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Q, R (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - S (Box 9, Folder 56 - 57)
    - T (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - U, V (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - W, X, Y, Z (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - New Commitments, 1978 September - 1979 July (Box 9, Folder 62)
- Donor records for the U2 Fund, 1961-1965; Accession 1983-A-016
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2040.
  - A-Bon (Box 1)
  - Boo-Cl (Box 2)
  - Co-Don (Box 3)
  - Doo-Graves (Box 4)
  - Gray-Jef (Box 5)
  - Jen-L (Box 6)
  - M-Na (Box 7)
  - Ne-Re (Box 8)
  - Ri-Sl (Box 9)
  - Sm-Th (Box 10)
  - Ti-Williams (Box 11)
  - Williamson-Z (Box 12)
- Yale Alumni Fund publications, 1964-2002; Accession 2007-A-038
  Scope and Contents
  No inventory available.
- Additional Materials, 1890-1967; Accession 2012-A-073
  - Board of Directors - Thirteenth Annual Report, 1903 June (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors - Meeting Minutes, 1890-1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Class Agents Record, 1914-1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee reports and documents, 1890-1891 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Solicitation correspondence, 1890-1919 (Box 3, Folder 4)